Eliott Davidson

Seattle WA | 206-437-8634 | eliott.davidson@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/eliott-davidson https://github.com/fussypuppet https://davidson.dev

Summary

I am a software engineer with a background ranging from social work to biology research. Whether it is answering unknowns about cellular function, translating confusing documents into approachable language, or designing code, I'm driven by a desire to distill complicated problems down to their core issues and deliver value, clarity, & efficiency.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Dart, Python, TypeScript, HTML, CSS **Frameworks:** React, Flutter, Node.js, Express.js, NextJS

United States Postal Service City Carrier Assistant

Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Other: Git, GitHub

Software Development Experience

Full-stack web development trainee General Assembly Seattle, WA Completed immersive web development training program involving over 500 hours of experience creating full-stack applications using React, JavaScript, & Python and mobile applications using Flutter & Dart.

Professional Experience

Mercer Island, WA 2017-present

| Kaplan Test Prep | Instructor / Course Administrator | Seattle, WA | 2015-2016 | |
|---|-----------------------------------|--------------------|-----------|--|
| Taught classes on standardized test-taking skills for the GMAT exam. | | | | |
| University of Washington | Post-Doctoral Fellow | Seattle, WA | 2014 | |
| University of Washington | Graduate Student | Seattle, WA | 2006-2013 | |
| Investigated the mechanics of cell division using a variety of biochemical and genetic techniques | | | | |
| TURN Community Services | Instructor | Salt Lake City, UT | 2003-2005 | |
| Taught basic life skills to and advocated for adults with developmental disabilities | | | | |

Education

| Software Engineering Immersive Program | General Assembly | Seattle, WA |
|--|--------------------------|--------------------|
| PhD, Molecular & Cellular Biology | University of Washington | Seattle, WA |
| BA, Biology | University of Utah | Salt Lake City, UT |